At that day... Kyuto's reset button
（深井平太）　＜あの日… Ｑ１０のリセットボタンを→
was pressed. Since then,
いわれるままに押してしまった あの日以来→
I don't exactly know a place where I can think properly
何をどこから考えればいいのか 全く分からず→
Something inside me has stopped
俺の中の何かが 止まってしまった＞
What is this feeling?
＜何だろう　この感じ＞
Everything seems so far away.
＜すべてが遠くに感じる＞
I don't understand the words they say,
＜言葉の意味が　よく分からない＞
I can't even see people around me,
＜人が人に見えない＞
It looks like a scenery.
＜風景は作りものみたいだ＞
I don't want to talk.
＜何で　喋らなきゃ なんないんだろう＞
I don't want to eat.
＜何で　食べなきゃ
I hear nothing.. I see nothing.
＜何も聞きたくない 何も見たくない＞
I'm just a human, still alive
＜自分は人間で　まだ生きていて→
Yet, Kyuto is not around anymore...
なのにＱ１０は　もういなくて…＞
I want to see you
＜会いたい＞
It's ok even if its not the real thing
＜たとえ 本物でなくてもいいから→
It's ok just to see her once
もう一度だけでいいから→
Even from a distance
遠くからでもいいから→
I want to see you
会いたい＞
Ah! Found it!
（柳）　あった！　はぁ～！
Ah! Found it! Look
（柳）　あった　ほ～ら　フフっ。
What about you? Have you found what you're looking for?
そっちも探し物　見つかった？
This is the worst
（月子）　最悪。
When did you charge her?
いつ仕込んだんですか？
Remember what you've said to Fukai-kun?
あなた　深井君にいったでしょう？
Fukai can only do nothing
((深井平太にしか　できないこと))
But...
((だけど…→
You definitely can't do anything
絶対にやってもらわなきゃ なんないこと))
So I was thinking that you only want Fukai-kun to press the reset button
（柳）　「そうか　深井君に　リセットボタン 押させたいんだ」って思った。
Therefore, thinking of its possibility
（柳の声） だから　万一のこと考えて→
I changed Kyuto's reset button
Ｑ１０のリセットボタン 入れ替えておいたの。
When the time comes that Fukai-kun will press the button
深井君が押した時は　Ｑ１０に→
I asked Kyuto to pretend to reset
リセットされたフリをするよう 頼んだの。
And then I want to see it with my own eyes and run here as soon as I can but,
そして　すきを見て 逃げて来いっていったんだけど→
With my appearance, it seems like they ran away properly
その様子じゃ ちゃんと逃げたみたいね。
Where is Kyuto?
Ｑ１０は　どこ？
Haven't you attached something like transmitters?
発信機みたいなの つけてんでしょ？
This is the transmitter.
だから　これが発信機なの。
No way
ウソ。
If I can't bring back Q10, something terrible is bound to happen
Ｑ１０を連れて帰らないと 大変なことになります。
"Something terrible"?
「大変なこと」って？
The world will be distorted.
世界が大きく歪んでしまう。
Then, explain it to Fukai-kun
じゃあ　そのことを 深井君に説明して→
Maybe you'll convince him to agree with you
納得してもらうしかないわよね。
That's impossible
それは無理です。
Why is that?
どうして？
People will only believe in what they see
人は見たものしか信じない。
Even if I explain it to him, he won't believe me
私が説明したって　到底 信じてもらえないと思います。
So, you let Fukai-kun see something in order to threaten him?
だから深井君に　目に見える形で 脅しをかけたってこと？
Is there any other way?
他に方法がありますか？
Of course there is
あるわよ。
To appeal heartily
心に訴える。
That will be a miracle
そんなの奇跡です。
We're still in year 2010 you know
２０１０年には　まだあるのよ→
that is a miracle
奇跡。
Right. It's Christmas
そっか　クリスマスなんだ。
Please Santa,
＜サンタさん　お願いです＞
Let me see Kyuto once again
＜もう一度 Ｑ１０に会わせてください＞
If such miracle happens...
＜もし　そんな奇跡を 起こしてくれるなら…＞
Wa~ wa~
≪わ～　わ～≫
wa~
わ～。
Snow! Snow! Snow!
雪！　雪！　雪！
Kyuto? Not in a loud voice!
（中尾）　声　出しちゃダメだって！ Ｑ１０？
I am seen~
（Ｑ１０） 見つかっちゃっただよ？
Let's run away~
（中尾）　逃げるんだよ　パオ～ン！
Kyuto!
Ｑ１０！
If such miracle happens
＜もし　そんな奇跡を 起こしてくれるなら→
I'm not going to ask anything in the future
この先　一生　何もいりません＞
Huh? What's with the tea? Then I didn't press the reset button?
えっ　何？　じゃあ　俺 リセットボタン　押してないってこと？
Something like that
（中尾）　そういうこと。
Then why is Kyuto staying in your place?
じゃあ　何で　Ｑ１０を かくまってるのが　中尾なの？
Because Professor Yanagi relies on me
だから　柳教授が 俺を頼って来たんだよ。
Eh~ But why you?
へぇ～ でも　何で中尾なんだろう？
I know what you feel but just to remind you This is my room!
気持は分かるけどさ ここは　俺の部屋だよ！
Oh Ok
あっ　はい。
Then why dressing like Santa?
あっ　じゃあ　何でサンタの格好？
We were told not to go out,
出かけちゃいけないって いわれたんだけど→
But Kyuto kept on telling me to try win the lottery
Ｑ１０が　どうしても 福引やりたいっていうから→
Then, in order to go, she has to disguise as Santa
じゃあ　変装して行こうってなって 時節柄　サンタ？
I see
なるほどね。
Did you have luck in lottery? Yes!
福引は当たったの？ そう！
Kyuto won! She won 3 times!
Ｑ１０が当てたんだよ なんと３等！
Look~~
見てろよ～。
I said, this is my room!!
だから　俺の部屋だっつ～の!!
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
Oh..voice is coming out
おぉ　声　出すなって。
You feel bad?
気分　最悪だろ？
It'll be 1 week today
（民子）　今日で１週間。
It's already been 1 week? why...
１週間も？　何で…。
I knew it by accident when I came
（民子）　私は　偶然来て知ったの。
He doesn't want you to know
深井君には 知らせてほしくないって。
You're happy right now
（久保） ((お前は　今　幸せなんだよ))
This is not your place anymore
((もう　ここは　お前の場所じゃ ないんだよなぁ))
I'm scared...
（民子）　怖いんだ…。
I know it myself because of my scared face.
自分でも分かってる ビビった顔してんだろうなって。
That is why I come here everyday not entering the ward
だから　毎日　ここ来るのに 病室　入れない。
If I am found out, Kubo-kun will feel bad. What will I do?
久保君が　よくないの 本人にバレたら　どうしようって。
I don't have the courage at all...
全然　勇気なくて…。
My love for him is not enough right?
私　愛が足りないのかな？
What are you doing?
何してんですか？
I'm putting back the original reset button
リセットボタン　元に戻してるの。
Eh?! Why? If you do that, Fujino Tsukiko will again...
えっ!?　何で？　そんなことしたら また　あの富士野月子が…。
This time, if reset button is to be pressed, Fukai-kun will do it himself
今度　リセットボタン押す時は 深井君が自分で押すと思うよ。
That's not possible
それは　あり得ない。
Fukai will definitely not press it
深井が絶対　自分で押すわけない 押す要素がない。
If you agree to communicate with Fujino-san, maybe you'll understand what's in her heart
（柳）　富士野さんと　心が 通い合うかもしれないじゃない。
Her heart? Talk to her? There's no way I'm going to do it!
心が？　通い合う？ んなわけないですよ　んなわけ！
If the button is pressed, the same thing happens again
押してしまったら また同じことになるんですよ。
No
違うわよ。
You wont understand what will really happen when you press this,
訳が分かんないうちに押すのと→
If given the chance to press it, the outcome is completely different
自分から考えて押すのとは 全然違う。
Isn't it Fukai will be the one to press it?
だから　深井が自分で押すわけ ないじゃないですか。
What could this be?
あら…　何だろう？　これ。
What is this?
これ　何？
I don't know
知りません。
Have you seen Kyuto?
（月子）　Ｑ１０に会えた？
As usual, Fukai-kun is easy to understand
相変わらず 深井君って分かりやすい。
Can you press the reset button?
リセットボタン 押してくれないかな。
No way
ヤダ。
If you leave Kyuto the way it is, the world will change significantly
このまま　Ｑ１０を置いておくと 世界は大きく変わってしまうの。
Because of your actions, two civilizations will go into extinction and one language will be destroyed
深井君のせいで　２つの文明が 滅びて　１つの言語が消滅する。
You didn't get my point?
ピンと来ないでしょ？
Right now, somewhere in this world, there are 900 million people starving
今も地球のどこかで ９億人が飢えている。
What I'm saying right now is, people are dying because of war and conflicts
今　こうしている間にも 戦争や紛争で人が死んで行ってる。
But for you, it has nothing to do with you
でも深井君には 関係ない話だもんね。
Right now, someone has lost an important person somewhere
今日も　どこかで 大切な人を失って→
Until that person is not able to shed out tear anymore
もう　涙さえ出ない人もいる。
Since,
でも　そんなの→
we don't have the same perspective, you won't be able to see it
見えなかったら ないのと同じなんだもんね。
If I'm not going to press it...
俺が押さなかったら…。
People die?
人が死ぬの？
5.6 million people
（月子）　５６０万人。
It's obvious. Fujino Tsukiko is lying
（中尾）　そんなことは富士野月子が ついたウソに決まってんじゃん。
That would be better
だったら　いいんだけどさ。
Hey, that one over there. Is that the desk of Fujioka?
（影山）　ねぇ　あそこに出てんの 藤丘の机？
Now you mention it, Fujioka's seat is lost
あぁ　そういえば 藤丘の席　なくなったよな。
I wonder if Fujioka is doing well? Somehow, I haven't seen him everyday
藤丘　元気なのかな？ 何か　毎日　見てないと→
I feel like there is great distance between us
ものすごく遠くへ行っちゃった ような気がするよな。
But there's a bakeshop just around the corner
でも すぐそこの　パン屋にいるって。
I know that
それは分かってんだけどさ。
Ah! By the way, I haven't seen Kyuto for such a long time
あっ　そういえば　久戸 長いこと見てねえけど→
What happened?
どうしたの？
I wonder what happened...
何でだろう…　なぁ？
You'll tell her to come to school tomorrow right?
明日から　学校　出て来るって さっき　いってたよね？
Ok! Eh? Really?
あっ　はい。 （良枝）　えっ　そうなの？
Huh? So it is. Something happened? Is she sick?
（大友）　えっ　そうなんだ ってか　何？　病気だったりした？
By the way, how come Nakao-kun knows her whereabouts?
（由起恵） ってか　何で中尾が知ってんの？
Ah! It's not like we're dating or something
あぁ…　付き合ってるとか そういうわけじゃないんだよ。
We're definitely not dating!
絶対　俺　付き合ってないよ！
Nobody is thinking that way
（宙） 誰も　そんなこと思ってないよ。
They're still there
でも　あれだよな。
As long as everybody can have a long rest. They couldn't care less
長く休んでも　みんな さほど気にしてないんだよな。
When I'll be in Canada, what will I do there?
俺も　カナダとか行ったら そうなっちゃうのかな？
Just like what everyone feels inside, we will all die eventually
みんなの中では 死んじゃったも同じみたいな。
Yamamoto is absent for almost a week
（小川　訪）　山本さ　今週　ほとんど 出て来てないんだけど→
Do you know something? No..
何か知ってる？ （恵美子）　さぁ？
I see. I'm sorry for asking. I thought you and Yamamoto are good friends
そうか　ごめん　山本と 仲いいのかと思い込んでた。
Seems like I'm mistaken. Sorry
先生の勘違い　ごめんな。
What's going on?
どうしたの？
I'm really the worst
私　最低なの。
What about?
何が？
I thought Yamamoto-san is my friend but,
山本さんのこと 友達だと思ってたのに→
I haven't noticed her absence at all...
休んでること 全然　気にしてなくて…。
And then...
それに…。
Aaa...But right now,
あぁ…　今だって　こうやって→
you're even listening to my complaints
影山君に グチグチ　話　聞いてもらって。
I'm really the worst
もう　ホント最低。
Sort of..
まぁね。
I'm sorry Hm?
ごめんね。 ん？
I'm about to say "I'm waiting for you upon your return from Canada"
カナダから帰って来るの 待ってるよって　いえなくて。
But no matter what, I can't say it
私　どうしても　いえないんだよね。
Maybe because I don't have expectations.
たぶん　結局 何にも信じてないんだと思う。
Even you don't have expectations
自分のことすら 信じてないんだと思う。
I also think so
俺もそうだよ。
Will I be ok in Canada? I'm still lost
ホントに　カナダでいいのか まだ迷ってるし。
Why don't we
俺達さ→
start believing in ourselves first?
まず　自分のこと 信じることから　始めよっか。
If you don't like it, nothing will eventually start
それ　やんないとさ 何も始まんないような気がする。
Am I wrong?
違う？
You're right
そうかも。
Only for now
とりあえずだけど。
Am I a bit arrogant?
ちょっと偉そうだった？
No
ううん。
Yeah, it's just for now right?
うん　まず　とりあえずだよね。
This feels good. Let's decorate together next year
いいもんですね また来年も飾りましょうよ。
Let's live together next year, ok?
来年は　一緒に住んでたりして　ね。
Well, we can't do that Why?
いや　それは　ないです。 どうしてですか？
We'll never know what lies ahead if we don't try
先のことなんて 分かんないじゃないですか。
I don't expect much from different things
僕は　あんまり　いろんなことに 期待しないことにしてるんです。
Somehow, I've managed to eat well. But there are worst situations that I avoid
何とか食って行けて　まぁ 最悪の事態さえ避けられれば→
Maybe I'm just plain stupid
それでオールＯＫなんじゃ ないかなって。
Hmmm~
ほぉ～。
Ah! Right now I just bore you. Sorry
あっ　今 つまんない男って思った？
No.. I think that's a brilliant idea
いいえ 素敵な考え方だと思います。
How come?
どこが？
Because that brings harmony in this world
だって　それって世界平和ですよ。
Eh?
え？
People in this world somehow manages to eat
世界中の人が 何とか食べて行けて→
and still can avoid any worst situations
最悪の事態を避けることが できますように。
Dad? Oh
（藤丘）　父さん？ （藤丘の父）　おう。
I'll wake him up. No.. let him sleep
起こすよ。 いいよ　寝させとけ。
Why did he draw this carelessly?
何で　こんな絵 平気で描けるんだろう。
After all, there are 4 people. He draws faces of anyone he randomly met
大体　今さら４人で どんな顔して会えっていうんだよ。
Don't say that
（藤丘の父）　いえてるな。
But when I look at this picture, he is not lost
（藤丘）　でも　俺　この絵　見てると 迷いがないっていうか→
"I have faith that he will come back"
「信じ切って描いてるんだな こいつ」って…。
When I look at this picture, he's probably realized
これ見てると　もしかしたら 叶うんじゃないか→
that you're coming
…って思えて来るんだ。
What I mean is, his wish is granted
っていうか　叶えてやりたい。
Christmas present
クリスマスプレゼント→
Don't open it
中　開けないでくれって いっといてくれ。
Eh? Because it's empty
え？ 中　空っぽだからさ。
I'll be with him next year I'll be your substitute
でも　来年は　中身入ってるやつと すり替えておくから。
You're going now? Oh
もう行っちゃうの？ おう。
Wait. Hm?
ちょっと待って。 ん？
This is all I got
（藤丘）　これ　全然　足りないけど。
No. It's ok
あれな　いいよ　もう。
Well, It's been decided
いや　困ってんだろ？
Then
じゃあ。
Take it all
いいよ　持ってけよ。
Then, I'll get this
じゃあ　そっちくれよ。
See you
じゃあな。
Maybe its true.. 5.6 million people will die?
ホントなのかな ５６０万人も死ぬって…。
For me, what Fujino-san said is probably true
私は　富士野さんの　いうこと ホントなんじゃないかなと思う。
5.6 million people?
５６０万人？
With regard to that number, I don't know what it means
数字のことは よく分かんないけど→
If there are certain things that naturally disappear,
本来なかったものが あるっていうのは→
I wonder if there's balance
バランスが崩れんじゃないかしら。
What's the worst thing that's gonna happen? Hmm~ that is
最悪のことが起こるってこと？ う～ん　でも　それは→
It has nothing to do with you if anything happens
深井君とは関係ない所で 起こるんじゃないかな。
Eh? Don't you think that's weird?
え？　そんなの変じゃないですか？
Because of my actions, as a consequence, something terrible will happen
俺のせいなら　俺が　ひどい目に 遭うべきなんじゃ…？
The world is not fair you know
世界は　そんなふうに 公平に　できてないのよ。
Therefore, it's getting complicated
だから 何だか複雑になっちゃって→
Worst things are going to happen
最悪なことが起こるんじゃない？
This came out from Kyuto's tooth
これ　Ｑ１０の歯から出て来た。
Eh? What is this?
え？　何ですか？　これ。
A letter from you at 88 years old
８８歳の　あなたからの手紙。
I've lived that long?
俺　そんな長生きすんだ。
Read it.
最後んとこ読んで。
Well, how will I read this?
ん？　いや… っていわれても　どこっすか？
Ah
あぁ。
"I want to say this to my 18-year old self" Right there
「１８歳の俺に　いいたい」。 そう　そこ。
"I loved Q10 as much as I loved the world"
「Ｑ１０を愛したように 世界を愛せよ」。
That's it
だって。
It's not working
ダメじゃん。
Try it Huh? Ok
やって。 ん？　あぁ。
please~~
お願いし～す！
So, it's impossible for us to have CD debut, huh?
やっぱりさ　ＣＤデビュー 無理なんじゃない？　ウチら。
I'll wish for something else then
じゃあ　別のこと願ってみよっか。
Ah... It's granted! What did you wish?
あ…。 ついた！　何　願ったの？
Yes...
うん…。
Wait! Where are you going?!
ちょっと　どこ行くのよ！
The producers will come! Tamiko!
もう来るよ　プロデューサーの人！ 民子！
My wish is granted
私の願い　叶うんだって。
My wish is..
私の願いはね→
I will be able to graduate.
私が落第して卒業できないこと。
And then, we're leaving this hospital together,
それで　退院した久保君と一緒に→
We're going to walk that road going towards the school gate
あの校門の坂道を ２人して上って行くこと。
If it's not possible next year, then we'll do it a year after next
来年がダメなら 再来年でもいいです。
If not possible a year after next, then we'll do it on the third year
再来年がダメなら その次の年でもいいです。
That's what I said deep in my heart...
心の中で　そういったら…。
Then this thing released light
光った。
Even if my wishes will not be granted...
他の願いはダメだったのに…。
There's the school gate,
校門→
that we can walk through together.
歩けるんだよ　２人して。
When that time comes, I
そん時はね　私→
will not wear wig
カツラなんか　かぶんないんだ。
My hair will remain red,
赤い髪のまま→
I will flaunt it so that everyone can see,
みんなに見せびらかすように→
I'll walk with you
久保君と歩くんだ。
Do you have hard toast? Oh sensei
（岸本）　ハードトースト　ありますか？ あっ　先生。
Oh! This store has it?
おぉ！　何だ　この店だったの？
Yes. We have hard toast but it'll be out soon,
はい　ハードトースト じきに焼き上がりますけど→
Can you wait for a while? Sure
待ちますか？ いい？
Then Excuse me
じゃあ。 おぉ　悪いね。
So how is it? You can still go on?
どう？　やって行けそう？
Yes
はい。
In order to do well with the society,
社会で　うまくやって行こうと 思ったら→
First of, it would be nice to become a dependable adult where a single person can rely on you
まず　頼りになる大人　見つけろ １人でいいから。
and half of that person's success
「これは」っていう 大人　見つかったら→
is influenced by the dependable adult
半分 成功したようなもんなんだから。
How's my idea? Do you have that person who is a good influence to you?
どうだい　いそうか？　そういう人。
I have
います。
Good for you! Who is that person?
よかったじゃん　どの人よ？
It's you. Principal
校長先生です。
Huh? Me? So it's me?
えっ？　俺？　俺かよ。
No way~ really?
ウソ～　マジで？
I'm also going to do my best...
頑張っちゃおうかな　俺　フフフ…。
Hard toast is now available
（店員）　ハードトースト 焼き上がりました。
Sensei, that baked bread is crunchy
先生　焼きたてのパンって 音がするんですよ。
Eh? Really? Oh I see
え？　本当？　へぇ　そうなんだ。
Ah~ This smells good
あ～　いい匂いだね。
I'm holding a warm bread
（岸本）　懐には　温かいパン。
I have a daughter and grandchild at home
家には　娘と孫。
And I have a student who believes in me.
俺を信じてくれる教え子もいる。
Yeah. I'm happy
うん　幸せだな。
What?
（深井武広）　何？
Dad...
父ちゃんさ…。
Do you love mom?
母ちゃんのこと愛してる？
Eh?!
えっ!?
You want me to say it? You want me to say it here? In the living room?
いうの？ ここで　いうの？　茶の間で？
Yup. I love her
うん　愛してる。
Most especially her neck
特に　うなじ　フフっ。
Well then...
じゃあさ…→
the way you love mom,
母ちゃんのことを愛するように→
is the same as you love the world?
世界を愛せる？
Now you mention it, I probably also have
っていうか それ　俺　もうしてるかも。
As I am loving your mother more,
かあちゃんを愛するがごとく→
I have loved the world already
世界を愛しちゃってるんだよ 俺的には。
Eh? Really? What do you mean of that?
え？　ホントに？ それって　どういうことなの？
In other words, I love your mother..
つまり かあちゃんを愛するってことは→
and I love the children that were born from your mother
かあちゃんが生んだ お前達を愛するってこと。
Which means, your mother gave birth to you guys
ということは かあちゃんを生んだ→
your mother and I love you guys
かあちゃんと　とうちゃんも 愛するんだよ　俺は。
I also love the kindness that your mother has given to us
かあちゃんに 親切にしてくれる人も愛するし→
That kind person is someone who loves kindness
その親切な人に 親切をしてくれる人も愛する。
Your mother can be ill-tempered, sometimes even bossy..
（武広）　かあちゃんに意地悪だった 上司も　回り回って→
That is the recent personality of your mother..
今の　かあちゃんの人格を つくってると思えば→
And I am also loving that personality too
それは　また　愛するべきなんだよ。
Your mother stands up composed. I just love everything about her
かあちゃんを成り立たしてるもの すべてを愛す。
That's all I can say
フフ…　そういうことよ。
Q-chan~~
（小川しげ）　Ｑちゃ～ん。
Welcome back~
（しげ）　おかえり～。
I love kind-hearted Kyuto...
＜Ｑ１０に親切な人を愛し…＞
Good morning Oh! Long time no see
おはようございます。 おう　久しぶり。
I love the way Kyuto's stand which is composed.
＜Ｑ１０を 成り立たせているものを愛する＞
The way I love Kyuto..
＜それが　Ｑ１０を愛するように→
is the same as the way I love the world
世界を愛すること＞
First of,
ここは　ひとつ→
will you press the reset button here?
リセットボタンを押しましょう。
Why are you saying something like that?
何で　そんなこというの？
Heita's heart is anxious
平太の心が　ザワザワしています。
If your heart continues to be like that, will you be alright?
このまま　一生 ザワザワしてていいのかな？
Will you be able to attain happiness?
それで　平太は 幸せになれるのかな？
I'll press the reset button.
押すよ　リセットボタン。
Why?
何で？
Because it's Christmas.
クリスマスだから。
I forgot to say the good news
言い忘れてた。
Kyuto said that the human brain's memory will always be there since it is made as such
Ｑ１０って　人間の脳の記憶に 残らない材質で出来ているの。
Eh?
え？
After 1 year, Kyuto won't be able to remember anything
１年ぐらい経つと Ｑ１０のことを思い出せなくなる。
I am also like her
私も同じようなのを塗ってるの。
All our memories will gradually fade away. You don't need to worry about it
だから私達のことは　徐々に 記憶が消えて行くから　安心して。
So, I must forget Kyuto?
俺が　Ｑ１０のことを 忘れるってこと？
It's a Christmas miracle,
クリスマスの奇跡→
Thank you. There's no way that I'll forget her
ありがとう。 忘れるわけないだろ。
I will not forget...
忘れるわけ…。
Fukai is going to press it after all
（中尾）　深井　やっぱり押すのか。
Then, for the last time, can you give me strength?
じゃあ　最後に　俺に 力を授けてくれませんか？
In other words, which
つまり　自分も　いずれ→
Kyuto can also do just like a robot To gather the power by all means.
Ｑ１０みたいなロボットを作れる っていうパワーを　ぜひ　俺に。
Grant you power?
パワーを授ける？
Puff!! Just like that.
パフ～!!　みたいな。
Puff! Puff! Puff! Puff!
パフ！　パフ！　パフ！　パフ！ パフ！
Granted!!
しかと受け取りました～!!
I have to say my farewell also to everyone.
みんなにも お別れの挨拶をします。
Eh?
え？
Goodbye
さようなら。
See you tomorrow.
あっ　また明日。
Bye.
（森永）　じゃあね。 （佐野）　また　明日。
Bye bye.
また明日ね。 （佐野）　バイバイ。
Goodbye.
さようなら。
Bye bye! See you tomorrow.
（由起恵）　うん　バイバイ！ （良枝）　また明日ね。
Goodbye.
さようなら。
See you tomorrow See you tomorrow. Bye bye!
（宮沢）　また明日。 （西村）　また明日ね　バイバイ！
Goodbye
さようなら。
See you tomorrow~!
明日ね～！
Oh! Till tomorrow then.
おっ　明日ね。
Goodbye. Oh! See you.
さようなら。 お～！　またね。
Everybody says "there's tomorrow"
みんな　「明日がある」って→
They believe in it no matter what.
何の疑いもなく信じてんだよな。
That's something that can't be taken away.
それを奪っては　いけません。
Nobody will take it away.
誰も奪っては　いけません。
Yeah. I think so too.
うん　俺も　そう思うよ。
But I don't want to forget Kyuto
でも　Ｑ１０を忘れんのは 嫌だな。
If the love of two person is truthful then,
２人の恋が真実ならば。
We'll meet again someday,
♪～　いつかは逢える
This is the truth There's no goodbye
♪～　これが本当の さよならじゃ　ないの
Eh...Hey that's too good.
えっ…　ねぇ　うま過ぎ。
Don't you think it's much better if it's hand drawn?
もっと手描きの感じのほうが いいんじゃないの？
Hand drawn? Yeah
手描き？ ああ。
By the way, when I say hand drawn, it doesn't mean you have to draw a hand...
あのね　手描きっていうのは 手の形を描くんではなくて…。
Nevermind.. just continue what you're doing.
まっ　いいけどね　そういうのも。
Rabbit! Wow! It's a rabbit!
ウサギ！ わっ　ウサギだったの！
Puff. This is good. Yup. This is good
パフ。 いいねぇ　うん　いいと思う。
You can't find a rabbit with 5 ears in this world.
この世に　耳が５本あるウサギが いないとは　言い切れないからね。
Rabbit Yup.
ウサギ。 うん。
Can I do it?
いい？
Heita
平太。
See you tomorrow
また明日。
The people of this era,
この時代の人は→
believes in something that they can't see.
目に見えないものを 信じることができるんですね。
You said, "there's no eternity" right?
あなた　「永遠は　ない」って いったわよね？
Yes
はい。
So what you see in year 2010,
２０１０年に見たものは→
are all eternal scenes, right?
あなたの中で　永遠の風景に なるんじゃないかな？
I see..
そっか…。
I can have my own "eternity"?
「永遠」って　自分で　つくれるんだ。
See! Even you think so!
ほら　あなただって 持ってるじゃない！
You believe in forces that can't be seen
目に見えないものを信じる力。
The brain's memory is made as such?
（小川の声） 脳に記憶させない材質？
Then, we have to forget Kyuto?
じゃあ　俺達 Ｑ１０のこと忘れちゃうのか？
Her memory will be gone after 1 year
１年ぐらいで 記憶　なくなっちゃうそうです。
But we can't do that
でも　なかったことには ならないんだよなぁ。
I wonder if everyone can do that
みんな　あったことなんだよなぁ。
Why? Somebody is coming?
何？　誰か来るの？
I have decided to accept boarders.
下宿人　置くことにしたから。
What?!
はっ!?
Why aren't you consulting me such important things like that?
何　そんな大事なこと 俺に何の相談もなしにやるかね。
But... a luggage is already inside.
だって　もう 荷物　入れちゃったのよ。
Eh?! I don't like it! Wait..I have to refuse! I have to refuse!
えっ!?　ちょっと　俺　嫌だからね！ いんの？　断る断る　ちょっと。
Excuse me
すいません。
Please take care of me from now on. I'm Yanagi Ritsuko~
今日から　よろしくお願いします 柳　栗子で～す。
No way! What is this? You mean Professor Yanagi is our boarder?
ウソ!?　えっ　何？ 下宿人って　柳教授だったの？
Why didn't you tell me?
何で　いってくれなかったの？
I have told you
だから　いったじゃないですか。
"Lets live together next year"
「来年は 一緒に住んでるかも」って。
Oi old hag! Hurry up, prepare the food already!
ハハハ… おい　ババア！　早く飯の支度！
Who's "old hag"? Hurry.
何が「ババア」よ。 ハハハ…　早く。
Sit down! Sit down! Ah... then...
どうぞ　どうぞ あっ　じゃ　じゃ…。
You too sensei. Sorry..
（柳）　先生も。 すいません。
After the surgery, 6 years have passed by so quickly
（武広）　え～　手術して　はや６年。
That wasn't fast. Feeling of "finally" right?
（深井ほなみ）　早くないよ ようやくって感じじゃない？
But that's 6 years you know. Right... so I should say "already" right?
（深井千秋）　でも６年だよ。 そっか　「もう」って気もするね。
Working hard with everyone, just like a normal family does,
みんなで　一生懸命なんてさ 普通の家族は　やらないもんね→
It was good experience
いい経験だったよ。
Next, from here on, Heita will say a word.
では　ここで　平太から ひと言あります　どうぞ。
Eh? Me? What will I say?
えっ　俺？　何か　いうの？
Eh....
え…。
With regard to me...
俺のことを…→
"Definitely will be cured" and "believing that it will happen"...
絶対に治るって ずっと信じてくれたから→
I will always carry it in my heart.
俺は　こうして ここに　いれるんだと思います。
Thank you
ありがとう。
When you come back, what's the first thing you're going to do?
戻ったら　まず　何する？
Let me see...
そうだなぁ…。
To climb the school gate's hill.
校門の坂　上る。
What is that?
何だ　それ。
And then to skip class and lie down at the rooftop
それから　授業サボって 屋上で　寝っ転がる。
humming next to someone who's singing,
隣で誰かが　鼻歌　歌っててさ。
While staring at the blue sky,
そんで　青空　見ながら→
whatever feelings is about to start from then on.
これから何か始まりそうな気持に なったりしてさ。
It's not "about to start"...
「始まりそう」じゃなくて…。
It has already started.
始まんだよ。
You didn't go back yet?
まだ帰ってなかったんだ。
We'll go home today.
今日　帰るの。
For the last time, let me see you smile.
最後くらい笑ってよ。
That will be impossible for awhile.
しばらくは　無理かな。
You'll be alright. You can go on living with a smile.
大丈夫 笑って暮らして行けるって。
But, this is definitely the one
（里子）((でもさぁ これとか　絶対そうだよ))
That's so impossible...
((そんなこと　あり得ないって… だから→
I had wild ideas during my high school days. Even if it's just your imagination,
俺の高校時代の妄想だって)) （里子）((たとえ想像でもさ→
you have this in your heart wherever you are,
これだけ　平太の心の中に いたってことは→
I'm sure someone out there is just like you.
本当にいたってことと 同じなんじゃないかな))
Eh... Maybe..
((えっ　ヘヘ…　そうかな？))
Kyuto was always watching you just like watching a scenery.
((Ｑ１０は　きっと深井平太と この風景を見てたんだね))
Ah! Lecture is about to start. Let's go.
((あっ　そろそろ講義の時間だから 俺　行くね))
Eh.. right now?
((えっ　もう？))
I told you. You will smile
ね？　笑ってたでしょう？
That girl... she will be my wife?
彼女が…　俺の奥さんになる人？
Yes. You were together until you died.
そう　死ぬまで一緒にいた人。
So now, you can forget...
あなたが忘れてしまっても→
that Kyuto was here. You just continue believing in people
Ｑ１０は　いるって 信じ続けてくれた人。
I'm sorry. Was I too loud?
ごめんなさい うるさかったですか？
No. Just nostalgic
いえ　何か　懐かしいなぁって。
This sound is nice right?
いいですよね　この音。
I was 88 years old yesterday,
＜俺は昨日　八十八才になった＞
I'm not going to die yet
＜まだ死ねそうもない＞
But, for my wife, she thinks that perhaps I'll die
＜しかし　妻のほうは たぶん　もうダメだ＞
My wife kept on asking me about Kyuto
＜その妻が　しきりに Ｑ１０の話ばかり聞きたがる＞
Kyuto is probably a creation of my imagination.
＜Ｑ１０というのは　たぶん 俺のつくった想像の産物なのだ＞
But..
＜なのに　俺は→
Whenever I look into something, Kyuto will probably show up
何かを見るたびに　Ｑ１０にも 見せたかったと思うのだ＞
I have first seen her in a business trip from moon to earth
＜初めての出張で見た 月からの地球＞
I heard that we had our honeymoon to a place where glacier melted
＜新婚旅行で聞いた 氷河の解ける音＞
The children took 1000 years to arrive.
＜子供達を連れて行った 樹齢１０００年の木漏れ日＞
What kind of miracle will you see?
あなたは どんな奇跡を見たのかな？
My wife doesn't have much time to live. So she wished to see me as 18 year old
＜余命少ない妻は １８歳の俺に会いたがった＞
To grant her wish,
＜その願いを叶えるため→
a robot that can time-travel was ordered
タイムトラベル用の ロボットを発注した＞
They copied the face and all data of my wife
＜顔は　妻の昔のデータを もとにした＞
I was surprised when they showed me the completed robot.
＜出来上がりを見せられた時 俺は驚いた＞
I never thought it would look like Kyuto.
＜まさに　Ｑ１０だった＞
Furthermore, they even made the same model.
＜しかも　型番まで同じの＞
In the middle of my springtime,
＜俺の青春の真ん中に→
It was certain, this Kyuto was here. I was convinced.
確かに　このＱ１０がいたと 確信した＞
Soon enough, I bid farewell to my wife.
＜もうすぐ　妻とは　お別れだ＞
But, there's a limit to my existence,
＜でも 俺が　いると思っている限り→
I will see the smiling face of my wife. It won't fade away.
妻の笑顔も　また この世から　なくならない＞
I didn't know that I would be following,
＜いるかどうか分からなかった Ｑ１０が→
Kyuto for 70 years. She was really there
７０年思い続けて 本当にいたように＞
Right now, I'm beside my wife drinking tea. And I say,
＜今　隣で　妻が　お茶を飲みながら いっている＞
"I'm certain that love, courage and peace,
＜「愛も勇気も平和も→
do exist in this world" and,
この地球上に　あると思えば きっと　あるのよ」と＞
I want to say this to my 18-year old self,
＜１８歳の俺に　いいたい＞
I loved Kyuto as much as I loved the world.
＜Ｑ１０を愛したように 世界を愛せよ＞
I believe it even though I can't see it now.
＜今は見えなくても 自分を信じろ＞
Someday, you'll believe it when you see it with your own eyes.
＜いつか　目の前に お前が信じたものが→
It will appear in some way. Until then.
形を持って現れる　その日まで＞